A Guide to the Papers of the Master Plan Committee of the University of Virginia,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Master Plan Committee of the University of Virginia
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-20/26/1.061
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers were an archival transfer from the Office of the President at an unknown date.
Scope and Content
Papers of the Master Plan Committee include correspondence, memoranda of meetings (minutes), reports by Sasaki, Walker & Associates, contracts with Sasaki, Walker & Associates and Johnson, Craven and Gibson, plans, and invoices. Reports of the Subcommittee on "Birdwood" and the "area East of Newcomb" are included.
Contents List
- Master Plan, 1959 September-1963 September (Box-folder 1:1)
- Master Plan, 1963 October-1964 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Master Plan, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Master Plan-Birdwood and Lambeth Field Updates, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Master Plan-Birdwood Subcommittee, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Master Plan Committee, 1963 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Master Plan Committee, 1964 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Master Plan Committee, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Master Plan-Contract with Chandler & Gibson-Electric Distribution System, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Master Plan-Contract with Hankins and Anderson-Water Distribution System and Fire Protection Requirements, 1963 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Master Plan-Contract with Johnson, Craven & Gibson-Area East of Newcomb Hall Development Plan, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Master Plan-Contract with Johnson, Craven & Gibson-Area East of Newcomb Hall Development Plan Architectural Drawing, 1963 January 11, Oversize.
- Master Plan-Contract with Sasaki, Dawson, De May Associates, Inc.-Birdwood and Lambeth Field Updates, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Master Plan- Contract with Sasaki, Dawson, De May Associates, Inc.-UVA Development Plan, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 2:3)
- Master Plan- Contract with Sasaki, Dawson, De May Associates, Inc. -UVA Development Plan Updates, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Master Plan- Contract with Sasaki, Walker and Associates, Inc.-UVA Development Plan Updates-Science Center Development Architectural Drawings, n.d.
  Oversize.
- Master Plan- Electric Distribution System, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 2:5)